How Charles Dickens wrote “A Christmas Carol” and created a tradition.
The Man Who Invented Christmas is a drama, history,
comedy film directed by Bharat Nalluri.
In 1843, despite the fact that Dickens is a successful writer, the failure of his latest book puts his career at a crossroads, until the moment when, struggling with inspiration and confronting reality with his childhood memories, a
new character is born in the depths of his troubled mind; an old, lonely, embittered man, so vivid, so human, that a whole world grows around him, a story so inspiring that changed the meaning of Christmas forever.
Charles Dickens, played by Dan Stevens.
Scrooge, played by Christopher Plummer.
Mr. John Dickens, played by Jonathan Pryce.
John Forster / Ghost of Christmas Present, played by Justin Edwards.
Kate Dickens, played by Morfydd Clark.
Haddock / Ghost of Marley, played by Donald Sumpter.
The Man Who Invented Christmas is a 2017 Christmas biographical comedy drama film about
Charles Dickens directed by Bharat Nalluri and written by Susan Coyne.
Based on Les Standiford's 2008 book of the same name, it stars Dan Stevens, Christopher Plummer, and
Jonathan Pryce, and follows Dickens (Stevens) as he conceives and writes A Christmas Carol.
The film was produced by Parallel Film and Rhombus Media.
It was released by Bleecker Street in the United States on 22 November 2017, and
by Thunderbird Releasing in the United Kingdom on 1 December 2017.
It received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of london, england, husband wife
relationship, based on novel or book, holiday, disabled child.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.